Guide to the Yamato Ichihashi Papers SC0071 SC0071
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Yamato Ichihashi papers
1918-1963
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ichihashi, Yamato
SC0071
6 Linear Feet
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The Yamato Ichihashi papers consist of a small amount of biographical material; reports, notes and surveys concerning foreign relations between Japan and the West, 1919-1928; uncorrected texts of the Washington Arms Limitation Conferences 1921-1922; reports and correspondence concerning the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1925; studies and surveys made by Ichihashi and others dealing with the Japanese immigration to the U.S.; articles and reviews by Ichihashi; class notes and syllabi of his Japanese History courses, and selected student papers. Boxes 5 through 8 contain correspondence, notes and some memoirs of the World War II relocation of Japanese and Japanese-Americans from the West Coast of the U.S. Boxes 9 through 12 contain 21 diaries covering the years 1943-1963 recording current international news events.
BIOGRAPHY
Yamato Ichihashi, born in Japan, came to the United States and received his A.B. in Economics from Stanford in 1907, A.M. in 1908, and his Ph.D. from Harvard in 1914. He returned to Stanford in 1913 to become Professor of Japanese History and Government. His special interests included studies of Japanese in America and relations between Japan and the United States. He participated as observer and secretary for the Japanese Government during the Washington Arms limitation talks and conferences and the Institute of Pacific Relations. After Pearl Harbor, Dr. Ichihashi and his family were "relocated" with others of Japanese ancestry to places away from the immediate West Coast of the U.S. Following the end of the War, Ichihashi and his wife returned to Stanford.
Provenance:
A gift of the Ichihashi estate to the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace in 1963; transferred to the Stanford University Archives in 1966. Additional gift of Woodrow Ichihashi, 1992.
Access Restrictions:
None.
World War, 1939-1945 -- Japanese Americans.; Japan -- History; Reports.; syllabi; Notes.; Ichihashi, Yamato; Ichihashi, Yamato; Stanford University. Department of History; Treat, Payson.; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949
- Professional
  - Biographical material; newspaper clippings concerning Japan's seizure of Manchukuo and Ichihashi's views on the possibility of war., Several documents and papers in Japanese. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Foreign relations between Japan and the West, including the United States (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Nation, concerning the Shantung question, 1919-09-20
    - Speech made by Baron Kato at Mr. Balfour's residence, 1921-12-19
    - Report on objects, organization, procedure and personnel of Washington Conference; "The Washington Conference and After, An Historical Survey," by Yamato Ichihashi, 1928
  - Washington Arms limitation talks, 1921-22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Uncorrected texts from Washington Arms limitation talks, 1921-1922
    - List of Japanese delegates
    - "The World Views of the Japanese People in the face of the Washington Conference" by Takashi Hara
    - Typescripts of speeches made by members of the Japanese delegation to clubs and organizations
    - Baron Kato's speech at the second session of the Conference, 1921-11-15
    - Baron Kato's speech at the third plenary session, 1921-11-21
    - Memorandum of committee of Naval Technical advisors, Washington, D.C, 1921-11-23
    - Sub-committee on Limitation of Armaments, first meeting, Dec 15, 1921
    - Subcommittee on Naval Limitation, third meeting, 17-Dec-21
    - Conference press release, 1921-12-20
    - Mr. Hanikara's remarks at the full committee on the limitation of Armaments, Dec 22, Dec 28, 1921
    - Committee on Limitation of Armament and sub-committee on naval Limitation, Dec 28, Dec 29, 1921
    - Kato's speech, 1921-12-30
  - Washington Limitation of Armament Conference: (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Resolutions, Adoptées par la Commission des Questions du Pacífíque et de l'Extrême-Oriental par la Conference
    - Extrait du Compte-Rendu de la Cinquieme Seance Sous-Commission des Quinze sur la Limitation Navale le, 25 Janvier, 1922
    - Compte-Rendu de la Déclaration de M. Sarraut
    - T.L. Ichihashi to E.D. Adams, Stanford, 8-Feb-22
    - Address of President Harding, undated
    - "Thoughts on certain phases of Japanese American relationships", undated
    - Several undated speeches presumably made by members of the Japanese delegation
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, Feb-Jul 2, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - List of Attendants at Institute of Pacific Relations Discussion, N.Y. Yale Club, 1925-02-22
    - Letter concerning plans for upcoming institute to be held in Honolulu, T.L., May 19, 1925
    - Address by Dr. Arthur L. Dean, June 30, 1925
    - Bibliography, alphabetically by title
    - Members of the institute, who's who in the Institute of Pacific Relations
    - Booklet of the Institute held in Honolulu
    - Information on Daily meditation, delegates of the American Group, officers and counselors of American Group
    - Statement of Australia's point of view
    - Outline of Canadian point of view
    - Outline of Chinese view of Pacific Relations
    - Outline of problems confronting Japan; Korea
    - Outline of statements for New Zealand
    - Outline of problem of the Philippines
    - Outline of the statement from the point of view of the United States
    - The important problems involved in Pacific relations from the viewpoint of Hawaii
    - Opening paper on Korea by Hugh Cynn, General Secretary, YMCA, Korea
    - Pacific Situation from the viewpoint of Hawaii by Romanzo Adams, professor, Univ. of Hawaii
    - Canada by John Nelson
    - A Chinese View of Pacific Relations by T.Z. Koo
    - Preliminary statement for the United States by Ray Lyman Wilbur
    - "The Far Reaching Effects of the Industrialization of the Far East", by C.C. Batchelder
    - "The Viewpoint of the Philippines" by Conrado Benitez
    - Opening Statement for Japan by Dr. M. Sawayanagi
    - "Industrialization of Japan" by Eakashi Komatsu
    - "Application of the Teachings of Jesus to Interracial and International Problems" by D.J. Fleming
    - "The Industrialization of China" by S.N. An-Young
    - American law in regard to Immigration, Landownership and citizenship by Payson J. Treat
    - "Buddhism facing Modern Inter-Racial and International Relations" by Professor M. Anesaki
  - Speeches delivered at Institute of Pacific Relations, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The Advantages and Disadvantages of the Industrialization of China" by S.T. Wen
    - "The Governmental Organization of New Zealand," by J.B. Gow
    - "Chinese Immigration in the Pacific" by T.A Chen
    - "The Economic Aspects of Immigration in the Pacific," by C.C. Batchelder
    - "Immigration in the South Pacific" by Stephen H. Roberts
    - "Historical Survey of Oriental Immigration: Origin, Nature and Development," by Payson W. Treat
    - "The Race Relation Survey on the Pacific Coast" by Dr. Robert E. Park
    - "What China Desires to see Rectified in her International Relationships," by Ta Chen
    - Address of President Ray Lyman Wilbur at Rotary Club, Honolulu, July 7, 1925
    - "The Economic Aspects of Immigration," round table discussions
    - "Standards of Living in the Pacific" round-table discussion
    - Origin, operation and accomplishments of the Honolulu institute Conference
    - Institute of Pacific Relations, Extracts from letters received from members, Dec 26, 1925
  - Institute of Pacific Relations., 1926 and undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Asilomar meeting, agenda, 1926
    - "Japan and World Relations," by David Starr Jordan, undated
    - "Westernized Japan" by Yamato Ichihashi
    - "The Racial Superiority"
    - "Abstract of Dr. Sawayangi's statement"
    - Outlines and texts of a series of lectures on Japan presumably by Ichihashi.
  - Studies of Japanese in the United States, 1915-31: (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Japanese Immigration, Its Status in California by Ichihashi, 1915
    - Letters concerning Ichihashi's book of immigration; anti-Japanese immigration pamphlets, circa 1920
    - "The California Alien Land Law and its Effect" by T. Takimoto, 1924
    - Studies made by Ichihashi on immigration restriction of orientals in the late, 1920's and 1930's
    - Interviews with School principals in Calif. discussing Japanese enrollment
    - Statistics on Japanese in Walnut Grove, California
    - Japanese in Fresno County
    - American feeling toward the Japanese in Los Angeles, ca1924
    - Japanese in other Western states
  - Studies of Japanese in the United States: (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Study of Japanese in the San Francisco florist business
    - Japanese in the San Joaquin delta region
    - "Supplementary report on the Japanese in the Watsonville District," by Y. Ichihashi
    - Studies of other writers works concerning Japanese immigration to the U.S.
    - Study of the situation of Japanese Nursery and its related business in San Francisco and the Bay Region
    - Law for Protecting Imin (Emigrants)
    - Annual reports of Commissioner- General of Immigration, 1900-07
    - Japanese on the Pacific Coast
    - "Some aspects of the Second Generation Japanese Problem in the United States"
    - Letter to President Woodrow Wilson (Undated and signed The Japanese Association of America) concerning the plight of Japanese in the United States
  - Round table discussions, (held at Yosemite National Park, California), 1936: (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Round table topic II - Japan, 1920-08-18
    - Entertainment notices
    - Roundtable topic III - U.S.S.R., August 21
    - Peace Machinery in the Pacific" by Kenkichi Yoshizawa
  - Correspondence, 1920-42 and undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous:
      - ALS. Lloyd M. Crosgrave to Ichihashi, 1920-03-24
      - T.L. Ichihashi to Professor Anesaki, June 5, 1924
      - T.L.S. George S. Mizota, Tokyo, Japan to Ichihashi, 1929-11-08
      - T.L. Charles G. Gardner to Ray Lyman Wilbur, 1936-09-19
      - T.L.S. Ray Lyman Wilbur to Ichihashi, 1936-10-21
    - Rockefeller Foundation:
      - T.L.S. Ray Lyman Wilbur to Ichihashi, 19-Oct-36
      - T.L.S. Ray Lyman Wilbur to Ichihashi, 21-Oct-36
      - T.L. Ichihashi to Ray Lyman Wilbur, 25-Oct-36
      - T.L. Ichihashi to Ray Lyman Wilbur, May 31, 1937
      - T.L. David R. Stevens to Ray Lyman Wilbur, June 16, 1937
      - T.L.S. Ray Lyman Wilbur to Ichihashi, June 18, 1937
      - T.L. Ichihashi, to Ray Lyman Wilbur, July 11, 1937
      - T.L. Ray Lyman Wilbur to A.F. Wright, June 20, 1937
      - T.L. Ray Lyman Wilbur to David H. Stevens, June 20, 1937
    - Oriental studies:
      - T.L.S. Warren D. Allen to Vincent Canzoneri, re: Oriental Music Instructor., May 8, 1941
      - T.L.S. W. D. Allen to Ray Lyman Wilbur, re: study of oriental music., May 8, 1941
      - T.L.S. Ray Lyman Wilbur to Ichihashi, re: appointment to Committee on Research., May 29, 1941
      - T.L.S. Inez G. Richardson, Hoover Library, to Ichihashi, 13-Oct-41
      - T.L.S. Ralph H. Lutz, Hoover Library, to Ichihashi, re: oriental history readings., Mar 2, 1942
  - Articles, reviews and talks by Ichihashi: (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Fourth of July speech at San Jose, 1917
    - Japanese Appreciation of American Diplomacy, 1918
    - The War and Japanese Intellectuals, 1918
    - Westernized Japan, Jan-19
    - Admiral Baron Kato, New Premier of Japan, Aug-22
    - Count Yamamoto, New Prime Minister of Japan, Nov-23
    - Review, Jan 1925
    - The Eventful Era of Taisho, Feb 1927
    - Japan's Influence and Interests in China, March 1928
    - Review of Japan's Economic Position by John E. Orchard, 1930
    - Review of Food Supply and Raw Materials in Japan by E.F. Penrose, 1930
    - Speech "One London Naval Conference", May 2, 1930
    - Review of Japan's Special Position in Manchuria by C. Walter Young, 1931
    - Review of Japan, An Economic and Financial Appraisal by Harold G. Moulton, 1931
    - Article "Economic Life in Japan" by Ichihashi, Nov, 1931
    - "Living Art" by Ichihashi, 1935
    - Review of Japanese Trade and Industry, 1936
    - Review of The Industry and Trade of Japan by S. Uyehara, 1936
    - Series of newspaper clippings re: Ichihashi speech in, 1938
    - Speech "Japanese American Relations", October 3, 1938
  - Article, reviews and speeches by Ichihashi, undated, and many untitled: (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "Japan and the War"
    - "Modern Japan as I see it"
    - "Some of the More Obvious Changes I saw in Japan"
    - "The Future of Western Civilization in Japan - Relatons between Japan and Foreigners"
    - "The Awakening of the Orient"
    - "Japanese Catastrophe and American Humanitarianism"
    - "Common-Sense in International Relations"
    - "The Pacific and the Orient"
    - "The Currency System of Japan"
    - "The Man from the East"
    - "Japanese Women"
    - "Study of Economics in Japan"
    - "A Leaf from my notebook"
    - "Understanding Japan"
    - "Americanizing the Japanese"
    - "Will Adams, the English Pioneer in Japan"
  - Reviews, articles and speeches by Ichihashi (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "The Imperial Family of Japan"
    - "The Reign of the Emperor Yoshihito, the Era of Taisho"
    - Review of The Japanese Population Problem by W.R. Crocker
    - Review of Economic Aspects of the History Of the Civilization of Japan
  - History Department correspondence, meetings and circular letters graduate study committee, 1929-32 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Papers: (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Japan and Future Labor Legislation"
    - "The Body Build of American-Born Japanese Children" by P.M. Suski, M.D., 1933
- Teaching
  - Outline for History 169 - History of Japanese Civilization (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Outline for History 116 - the History of Japan (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Outline for Economics I (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Student Papers, 1921-1924: (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Admiral Baron T. Kato" by J. B. Millet, 1921
    - "The Thirty-Six views of Fuji-Yama" by Harrison Chandler
    - "A Quota for Japan?" by Reginald Bell
    - "The Twenty-One Demands as made by Japan on China in 1915" by N.T. Nowell, 1923
    - "Japanese Conception of Family and its Influence upon the Government" by Harriett Greenwood, 1924
    - "The Japanese Mikado versus the English King" by Hal Rorke, 1924
  - Student Papers, 1925-1938: (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Important Events in China-Japanese Relations from 1894 to 1924 stressing the Shantung Question" by Elizabeth Renton, 1925
    - "The Organization, Composition and Budgetary Procedure in the Imperial Diet of Japan" by Victor Hunt Harding, 1925
    - "The Submarine Question at the Washington Conference," by Ellen Mead, 1925
    - "The Imperial Diet of Japan" by Inez Grosfield, 1926
    - "The Development of Japan's Trade Since 1913" by Clem Imost, 1936
    - "Literary Creations by Women of the Heian Period" by Audrey Brumfield, 1938
    - Series of essays on Japanese government and foreign affairs by Norris N. Everett, 1938
  - Student Papers: Delmer Brown, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Application of the Kellogg Pact to the Manchurian Incident of 1931" by Delmer M. Brown, 1939
    - "Political Factors Underlying the Marked Development of National Unity in Japan between 1573 and 1598" by Delmer Brown, 1939
  - Student Papers, authors B - K, 1939: (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "The Mongol Invasion of Japan" by Frank Bush, 1939
    - "The Hokku" by Jean Campbell, 1939
    - "The Rise of the Military Families Taira and Minamoto" by W. Doheny, 1939
    - "Pictoral Art of the Ashikaga Period" by Ruth Harris, 1939
    - "American Policy toward the Manchurian Incident" by Tsuneo Buddy Iwata, 1939
    - "The Historical Significance of the Japanese Isolation Policy 1638-1854" by Don P. Kennedy, 1939
  - Student Papers, authors L - S, 1939-1940: (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "The Open Door" by Phyllis Ladensohn, 1939
    - "Cabinet-Diet Relationship, 1884 to 1938," by Dallas A. Tueller, 1939
    - "Roman Catholic Christianity in Japan 1549-1638" by Masago Shibuya, 1940
  - Student Papers, 1941-1942: (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Japanese Haiku Poetry" by Matsuye Takeshita, 1941
    - "Far Eastern Agreements of the Washington Conference" by Matsuye Takeshita, 1941
    - "The Internal Economic Structure of Japan and Her International Economic Position" by Walter A. Radius, 1942
  - Student Papers, authors A - H, undated: (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "The Russo-Japanese Conflict Negotiations" by K. Asakawa
    - "Life of Hideyoshi" by Muriel Bogge
    - "The Operation of the Gentlemen's Agreement between 1911 and 1921" by Carol Gray
    - "Government of Japan" by William E. Hagen
  - Student Papers, authors I - T, undated: (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Series of papers on Japanese Government by Buddy Iwata
    - "Japanese Poetry and its Influence upon the Imagist School of Europe and America" by Kay Kitagawa
    - "The Imperial Prerogatives of the Japanese Emperor" by Ethel Oliver
    - "The Romance of a Sixteenth Century Adventurer, Mendes Pinto, In East Asia," by Matsuye Takeshita
  - Student Papers, authors V and unknown, undated: (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Federal Action Concerning Japanese Immigration" by Mary Valentine
    - "Development of the Constitution"
    - "The Japanese Woman in the Home"
    - "The Downfall of the Shogunate and the Restoration of the Imperial Regime, 1868."
- War Relocation
  - War Relocation, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 2 Receipts for U.S. War Savings Bonds purchased by Ichihashi, April 8, May 8, 1942
    - Information bulletin concerning living routines at relocation assembly center, May 26, 1942
    - Report on Conditions at Manzanar Relocation Center, May 26, 1942
    - T.L. Ichihashi to Payson and Jessie Treat, re: conditions at Manzanar., June 7, 1942
    - American Citizens' Reaction to the War Relocation Work Corps, June 1, 1942
    - "Concentration Camp: U.S. Style" by Ted Nakashima, June 15, 1942
    - National Student Relocation Council questionnaire, June 23, 1942
    - T.L. Ichihashi to Dr. Wilbur, re: conditions at relocation center., July 3, 1942
    - T.L.S. Ichihashi to L.W. Frader, assistant manager, Santa Anita Assembly Center, re: Japanese books in Ichihashi's possession., July 10, 1942
    - Request for repatriation form, 18-Jul-42
    - T.L.S. Howard H. Quint to Ichihashi, re: happenings at Stanford, July 21, 1942
    - T.L.S. Edgar E. Robinson, Acting President, Stanford University, to Ichihashi, re: letter of recommendation Robinson wrote on behalf of Ichihashi concerning relocation to Tule Lake, July 23, 1942
    - Manual for Block Representatives, Tule Lake, July 30, 1942
    - T.L.S. Grayson N. Kefauver to Ichihashi, re: an educational program for Japanese in relocation centers., July 30, 1942
    - T.L.S. W.O. Mendenhall, President, Whittier College to Ichihashi, re: thank-you note, July 31, 1942
    - T.L.S. Ray Lyman Wilbur to Ichihashi, re: Ichihashi's move to Tule Lake., July 31, 1942
    - T.L.S. Common sense magazine editor to Ichihashi, re: possibility of writing an article on Japan, 3-Aug-42
    - A.L.S. Charles Barker to Ichihashi, re: happenings at Stanford., 3-Aug-42
    - T.L.S. George H. Knowles to Mrs. Payson J. Treat re: renting vacant Ichihashi home, Aug 4, 1942
    - T.L. Robert E. Gibson to Dr. Grayson Kefauver re: consideration for Ichihashi at relocation center., Aug 4, 1942
    - A.L.S. Jessie Treat to Ichihashi, re: rental of home, Aug 5, 1942
    - T.L.S. Payson Treat to Ichihashi, re: happenings at Stanford, Aug 5, 1942
    - T.L. Circular, re: conditions at Manzanar Relocation Center, Aug 6, 1942
    - A.L.S. C.S. Stottenberg to Ichihashi, re: Stanford campus activities., Aug 8, 1942
    - A.L.S. D. Kuyon(?) to Ichihashi, re:. Santa Anita Assembly Center, Aug 10, 1942
    - T.L.S. Kay Sugahara to Ichihashi, re: Santa Anita Assembly Center riot., Aug 10, 1942
    - A.L.S. Ichihashi to Edgar [Robinson], re: trip to Tule Lake Relocation Center, Aug 12, 1942
    - T.L.S. Grayson N. Kefauver to Ichihashi, re: letter of introduction., Aug 12, 1942
    - Form letter dated from Department of Justice, Alien Enemy Control Unit, Aug 13, 1942
    - T.L.S. Robert E. Gibson to Ichihashi, re: educational work possibilities, Aug 12, 1942
    - T.L.S. Robert Warren to Ichihashi, re: renting Ichihashi home., Aug 13, 1942
    - T.L.S. Kay Sugahara to Ichihashi, re: Conditions at Santa Anita, Aug 18, 1942
    - T.L.S. Edgar Robinson to Ichihashi, Aug 21, 1942
    - T.L.S. Editor of Common Sense Magazine to Ichihashi re: article on Japan
    - War Relocation Authority (WRA) notice of interview, Sep 3, 1942
    - T.L.S. Carolyn Strouse Baer to Ichihashi, re: letter of appreciation for his fine teaching, Sep 7, 1942
    - WRA instruction, re: procedure in handling complaints made by colonists, Sep 29, 1942
    - "Outlawing Japanese-Americans?" Article in Common Sense, Sep-42
    - Memorandum re: furniture factory workers, Oct 2, 1942
    - Charter of Tule Lake Relocation Project, Oct 13, 1942
    - A.L.S. Lynn White to Ichihashi, re: hopes for removal of restrictions, Oct 19, 1942
    - A.L.S. Olive Cole Smith to Ichihashi, re: regrets over relocation, Oct 26, 1942
    - T.L.S. _____? to Ichihashi, re:. discontinuing of purchase of bonds., Nov 9, 1942
    - T.L.S. Payson Treat to Ichihashi,., Nov 13, 1942
    - T.L. Ichihashi to Treat, re: Tule Lake Conditions, Nov 20, 1942
    - T.L. Ichihashi to Edgar [Robinson], re: conditions at Tule Lake, Nov 22, 1942
    - WRA - office memorandum, Nov 24, 1942
    - T.L.S. Payson [Treat] to Ichihashi, Nov 24, 1942
    - Community Frontiers, vol. 1, #4, Nov-42
    - Supplement to balance sheet, Nov-42
    - WRA memorandums, Dec 14, 1942, Dec 18, 1942
    - Tule Lake Project Personnel list, Dec 10, 1942
  - War Relocation - miscellaneous papers and undated., 1942 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Notice and general instructions to Japanese seeking repatriation.
    - By-Laws of Tule Lake Co-operative Enterprises, Inc.
    - Instructions for keeping personal family accounts.
    - "What we're fighting for" by Japanese in U.S. Army.
    - Several documents or letters in Japanese.
    - Evacuee Problems, his adjustment. Administration and future.
    - Notes made by Ichihashi concerning the evacuation to the Santa Anita Assembly Center.
  - War Relocation - survey, lists of pupils and teachers of the center schools., 1942 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Santa Anita Assembly Center Administrative notices, 1942-Apr-Sep, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Council Meeting Minutes [Tule Lake], 1942-Sep 26-Oct 27, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sharp Park Mirror - mimeograph publication, Aug 22-Oct 24, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - War Relocation, 1943, January -June (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - WRA memo, Jan 5, 1943
    - T.L.S. Daisuke Kitagawa to Ichihashi, re: Juvenile Problem Committee., Jan 6, 1943
    - Various WRA memos.
    - T.L.S. Harvey M. Coverley, WRA, to Ichihashi, re: program planning problems., Jan 15, 1943
    - Study - Age of American-born and foreign-born Japanese, Tule Lake Relocation Project by Nativity and Sex, Jan 29, 1943
    - T.L.- National Geographic Society to Ichihashi, re: refund., Feb 15, 1943
    - Harvey M. Coverley, WPA, re: meetings.
    - A.L.S. Lynn [White] to Ichihashi, Feb 18, 1943
    - T.L.S. Payson Treat to Ichihashi, Feb 22, 1943
    - T.L. Major Sam L.A. Marshal, re: swearing allegiance to the U.S., Feb 23, 1943
    - Questions and answers about the family internment camp, Feb 26, 1943
    - Warnings re: removal of food from Mess Halls, Mar-43
    - Planning board memo-, Mar 4, 1943
    - T.L.S. Hiroshi Kaniko to Ichihashi, re: Young People's Christian Conference., Mar 20, 1943
    - T.L.S. Payson Treat to Schumashi, Mar 22, 1943
    - WRA memos, Apr-43